3437 80th Street, Jackson Heights NY ⊙

+1 518 466 7739

joe-flaherty.me ⋒

thepotter782@gmail.com @

joseph-flaherty-b4659a7b in

SKILLS

Java C# TypeScript JavaScript ETL Python CSS NoSQL MySQL C++

Unit Testing

FRAMEWORKS

Angular Spring Serverless AWS

EC2 -

S3 -

Load Balancing -

Lambda -

DynamoDB -

RDS -

API Gateway -

SageMaker -

CloudFront -

CloudWatch -

Unity Android iOS Oculus

SOFTWARE

IntelliJ Rider Eclipse Git Node Docker Jenkins Tomcat

Slack

Jira Confluence Visual Studio New Relic Adobe CC

Illustrator -

InDesign -

Photoshop -

Premiere -

PROFILE

Full stack developer with 15 years of experience building web, game, and backend platforms. Helped start a company and spent 9 years as lead developer working on all parts of a large multiframework platform. Looking to join a meaningful development team to provide a vast array of development skills.

WORK EXPERIENCE

Self Employed - New York, NY

Game Developer | 2022 - Present

- Working as sole developer, artist, and designer, building the game from the ground up.
- Developing Angular-based puzzle game that mixes document mystery and ancestry research. The
 main character uncovers the root cause of a family curse while trying to find out how to stop it
 from happening to her. Give it a try here or see the original Unity code here.

Sciolytix (formerly Selleration) - New York, NY

Lead Product Architect | 2013 - 2022

- Starting as a single-person development team, built the flagship product UPtick from the ground up. UPtick is a simulation training platform built in Java, Unity, Oculus, iOS, Android and Angular.
- Acted as system administrator keeping all services running on a variety of Amazon services (EC2, S3, Cloudfront, RDS, DynamoDB, Lambda, and more).
- Communicated directly with clients, assisting in technical support, design, and product installation.
- Collaborated with the leadership team to build goals for the development team.
- Developed machine learning pipeline used to predict success of users.

Kuma Reality Games - New York, NY

Developer | 2011 - 2013

• Worked on a social media platform called ScatterRadio which allowed users to record and stream audio messages. Worked primarily in Flash, Unity HTML, MySQL, and PHP.

BrandGames - New York, NY

Lead Developer | 2009 - 2011

 Developed marketing and training games for a variety of Fortune 500 companies, working primarily in Flash, HTML, Unity, SCORM, and ASP.net.

Rebel Monkey - New York, NY

Game Developer | 2008 - 2009

Developed Java servers for a variety of multiplayer Flash games hosted on early Amazon EC2.

VOLUNTEERING

Tech for Campaigns

Frontend Developer | 2018 - Present

- Working on an all-volunteer team, setting up WordPress sites for grassroots political campaigns.
- Train new volunteer frontend developers.

Showing Up for Racial Justice, NYC Chapter

Communications Volunteer | 2020 - Present

- Help manage communications to more than 23,000 members through the EveryAction CRM.
- Train new volunteers on how to use EveryAction and communicate with membership.

EDUCATION

Rensselaer Polytechnic Institute - Troy, NY

Bachelor of Computer Science | 2008